Sitemap1

__

CUSTOMER SUPPORT
----------------

Looking for help? You're in the right place. Type your message and we will get back to you in a second or less.

 +95746373939030 [info@sns.com](mailto:info@sns.com) [Office locator](https://new.shopandship.com/en/contact)

* Login

* Eng
* عربي

### Terms and Conditions

Select Country
==============

Select Country Angola Armenia Australia Azerbaijan Bahrain Bangladesh Benin Bulgaria Burkina Faso Cameroon Congo Cyprus Czech Republic Djibouti Egypt Ethiopia Georgia Germany Ghana Greece Guinea Hong Kong India Indonesia Iraq Jordan Kazakhstan Kuwait Lebanon Liberia Libya Lithuania Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Mauritius Morocco Nepal New Zealand Nigeria Oman Pakistan Qatar Reunion IS Saudi Arabia Senegal Sierra Leone Singapore Somalia Somaliland Sri Lanka Switzerland Tanzania Thailand Togo Tunisia Turkey Uganda United Arab Emirates United Kingdom Uzbekistan Zambia

TERMS AND CONDITIONS
====================

Shop and Ship Standard Terms and Conditions

* Australia: To view the Shop & Ship Australia Terms and Conditions, please click [here](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/australia).
* Indonesia: To view the Shop & Ship Indonesia Terms and Conditions, please click [here](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/indonesia).
* UAE: To view the Shop & Ship UAE Terms and Conditions, please click [here](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/uae).
* Lebanon: To view the Shop & Ship Lebanon Terms and Conditions, please click [here](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/lb).
* Yemen: To view the Shop & Ship Yemen Terms and Conditions, please click [here](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/terms-conditions-yemen).
* KSA, Egypt & Jordan: To view the Shop & Ship Terms and Conditions, please click  [here](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/terms-conditions-ksa).
* United Kingdom: To view the Shop & Ship UK Terms and Conditions, please click [here](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/terms-conditions-uk).

This Shop and Ship Account agreement is made and entered into by and between Aramex International LLC (“**Aramex**”, “**we**”, “**our**”) and the individual or entity identified in the Shop and Ship Application Form (referred to as “**You**” or “**your**”). Your use of the Shop and Ship service (“**Service**”) is subject to these terms and conditions (“**Terms and Conditions**”). The Service is provided to you under these Terms and Conditions and any updates thereof or amendments thereto, and any related operating rules and policies that are published from time to time by Aramex on the Shop and Ship website ([www.shopandship.com](http://www.shopandship.com/)).

The Shop and Ship Account (“**Account**”) shall be subject to the following Terms and Conditions:

**Definitions and Interpretation**

“**Shipment**” means all documents or parcels that travel under one waybill and which may be carried by any means Aramex chooses, including air, road or any other carrier. A “waybill” shall include any label produced by Aramex’s automated systems, air waybill, or consignment note and shall incorporate these Terms and Conditions in full.  Every Shipment is transported on a limited liability basis as provided herein.

a. "**Airfreight Convention**" means whichever may be applicable of the:

b. Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Carriage by Air signed at Montreal on 28 May 1999; or

Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules relating to International Carriage by Air, signed at Warsaw on 12 October 1929; either unamended or amended by the Hague Protocol 1955; at Guatemala City 1971, by the additional Protocol No 3 of Montreal 1975 and/or by the additional Protocol No. 4 of Montreal 1975.

"**Dangerous Goods**" means cargo which is noxious, hazardous, inflammable, explosive or offensive (including radioactive materials) or may become noxious, hazardous, inflammable, explosive or offensive or radioactive or may become liable to cause damage to any person or property whatsoever whether prescribed by laws or otherwise.

"**Goods**" are any goods or items which are the subject of the Service provided by Aramex to you under these Terms and Conditions.

"**Government Authorities**" means, without limitation, all government or semi-governmental departments and agencies with responsibility for the import and export of goods, the collection of revenue on the import and export of goods and the transport of those goods.

**Services**

1\. The Service enables you to make purchases in countries identified [here](https://shopandship.com/ourstory) (and such other countries as may be notified by Aramex from time to time) using a personalized physical address in the respective country (“**Shop and Ship Location**”). On delivery of the purchased item to the respective Shop and Ship Location, Aramex will process the Shipment and arrange for delivery of the item to the address and country stated in the Application Form (“**Delivery Address**”). Shipments cannot be delivered to Post Office box address.

**2\. Registration and appointment of Aramex as your agent**

To register for the Service, you will need to complete the Shop and Ship Application Form (“Application Form”), set up an Account on the Website, and pay the one-time registration fee (“Account Fee”).  Registration for access to the Service is open to individuals who are 18 years of age or older (or the legal age of majority in your country). By registering for our Service you are appointing Aramex as your agent for the receipt of, and organization of transportation for, your packages and you authorize Aramex to receive any and all packages addressed to you that are delivered to the respective Shop and Ship Location.

**3\. Receipt and Delivery**

The Service by Aramex includes the receipt of your packages at the Shop and Ship Location and transporting such packages to your Delivery Address. You are solely responsible for providing to and confirming with the sender the correct Shop and Ship Location, including your personal account number, and you understand that any incorrect information may result in non-delivery or delayed delivery of items, or incurring additional fees under this clause 3 for which you will be held accountable. Any Shipment that is unable to be delivered to you (for reasons including, without limitations, your failure to pay, take delivery, give proper instructions, including failure to clearly address the package, your failure to confirm your Shipment is acceptable for entry into the destination country, failure to use correct Shop and Ship Location, failure to update your Delivery Address, or you are unable to be contacted after reasonable attempts to do so) will be deemed an Uncollected Good or Unclaimed Good and Aramex reserves the right to deal with that Shipment in any lawful manner it considers appropriate, which may mean the package is discarded, destroyed, returned to sender, or auctioned.

The packaging of your Shipment for transportation is solely the shipper’s responsibility. Aramex accepts no responsibility for loss or damage to the Goods caused by inadequate or inappropriate packaging. Aramex has no obligation to repackage any Shipment for any reason. In the event Aramex repackages your Shipment, Aramex will charge you for such repackaging services provided by Aramex.

To ensure delivery of your Shipment, you are responsible for confirming items purchased in a Shop and Ship Location are shipped to the corresponding Shop and Ship Location address, and not to a different Shop and Ship Location address, which may result in non-delivery of items due to applicable laws, rules, regulations, etc.

**4\. Postage or payment outstanding**

Aramex will not accept on your behalf any items on which postage is outstanding and payable or Cash on Delivery items unless prior arrangement has been made by you with Aramex, and Aramex has agreed to it at its sole discretion. Any such agreement may give rise to liens or other interests at law and Aramex reserves the right, notwithstanding the foregoing, to lawfully enforce any such interests howsoever arising.

**5\. Accountable Mail**

Aramex will not accept certified, registered, insured, or express mail (“Accountable Mail”) on your behalf unless otherwise requested by you and agreed by Aramex subject to certain requirements (see clause 32).

**6\. Inspection**

Aramex, without liability, reserves the right to open and inspect all items delivered to the Shop and Ship Location to determine the nature or condition of the Goods or to determine their ownership or destination.

**7\. Service restriction**

Aramex reserves the right to abandon carriage of any Shipment at any time after acceptance when such Shipment could possibly cause damage or delay to other Shipments, equipment or personnel, or when any such carriage is prohibited by law or is in violation of any of these Terms and Conditions.

**Account** **Fee** **and Shipping Fees**

8\. You agree to pay Aramex a one-time Account Fee as identified [here](https://shopandship.com/membership), inclusive of applicable VAT, upon registration for the Service. The Account Fee is non-refundable unless you qualify for the Money Back Guarantee.

9\. Shipping fees will be charged at the rate applicable to your shipment set out in the website (“Shipping Fees”) or as modified by Aramex from time to time. High volume items will be subject to additional fees as set out in the website [here](https://shopandship.com/faq/odd-size-shipments). Shipping Fees are exclusive of all government taxes, and import VAT applicable on total invoice value of goods, including insurance, freight, incidental charges related to transportation, and on custom duties (“Import VAT”), and any other third party charges, including customs duty, that are payable on the shipment of your Goods, and you understand and agree that all such taxes, VAT, import VAT and third party charges will be paid by you prior to or upon delivery of your Shipment. 

a. Switzerland Shop & Ship Location: Shipments delivered to the Switzerland Shop & Ship Location will be subject to: (i) applicable customs clearance fees, or (ii) bonded area fees in relation to any Shipment from outside Switzerland. The aforesaid charges incurred by Aramex shall apply to all Shop and Ship accounts and you will be liable to pay irrespective of you rejecting delivery of the Shipment. Non-payment of said charges may lead to immediate deactivation of your Shop and Ship account.

b. Handling Fee: Aramex is entitled to charge a reasonable handling charge per Shipment in respect to normal handling and administrative functions related to the Service, and you agree to pay such handling fee.

10\. You agree to pay all applicable Shipping Fees and other charges including custom duties and Import VAT for any Shipment that has been ordered on your Account when requested to do so by Aramex and regardless of the person who placed the order. The aforesaid shall apply to all Shop and Ship accounts including individuals’ and entities’ accounts. It is your responsibility to ensure your shipment includes an invoice or you upload an invoice on your Account for the respective Shipment within the mandatory period notified to you. In the event an invoice is not provided, Aramex will have the right to provide an estimated value with no further liability to you should you not provide an invoice or amend the estimated value within the time period included in the email notification sent to you at the time your Shipment is added under your Account, and included under Activity Update and you will be solely responsible for any misdeclaration. You are solely responsible if you or a third party changes the declared value on any Aramex platform, and Aramex assumes no responsibility for such declared value, including a finding of mis-declaration by a Customs authority. Assuming you have provided accurate information for the customs declaration and Customs does not dispute the value, the amount of Import VAT and customs duty actually charged by your country’s Customs authority may differ from the amount you paid Aramex. In the event, the actual customs duty and Import VAT is more than the estimated amount charged by Aramex, Aramex shall have the right to charge you and you will pay the difference, along with any penalty, fine, expense incurred by Aramex due to inaccurate information provided by you.  

a. Payment Options

**i. Pay Now**: You will be notified once your Shipment leaves the origin facility along with the total Shipping Fees. You will be further notified once your Shipment clears customs including customs duties, Import VAT and any other fees paid. You will be prompted to log into your Account and make an online payment for the Shipping Fees and any other fees including customs duties and Import VAT.

**ii. Auto-Pay**:

1\. Aramex may offer you the Auto-Pay option, if applicable in your country, for the payment of the Shipping Fees and any other fees including customs duties and Import VAT.  If you select the Auto-Pay Option on our Website:

a. You authorize Aramex to save and store your nominated credit/debit card or PayPal account information.

b. You authorise Aramex to charge your nominated credit/debit card, or PayPal account, for the amount of the Shipping Fees and any other charges including customs duties and Import VAT.

c. You warrant the acceptance of the Shipping Fees and any other charges including customs duties and Import VAT by your credit/debit card provider, or PayPal, and undertake to reimburse Aramex for any such charges if payment is not received from your credit/debit card provider, or PayPal.

d. Upon expiration of your nominated credit/debit card, or PayPal account, Aramex will notify you and require you to update your Account with a valid credit/debit card, or PayPal account. In the event you do not update your Account with a valid credit/debit card, or PayPal account, the Auto-Pay option will no longer be available to you until you provide such updated information.

e. You will be solely responsible for any currency conversion expense in the event your nominated credit/debit card or PayPal account is not in the respective currency of the Shipping Fees and any other charges including customs duties and Import VAT.

f. In the event that you elect to Opt-Out of the Auto-Pay option, you undertake to arrange for the collection or redelivery of any Shipment which Aramex holds and you acknowledge that otherwise any Shipment will become an Uncollected Good. You acknowledge and agree that opting out of the Auto-Pay option does not terminate your Account and does not relieve you of any obligation to pay all amounts owing to us under your Account by a method of payment that is satisfactory to us.

2\. If you do not select the Auto-Pay option, you undertake to provide credit/debit card, or PayPal account, details and an authority to charge the credit/debit card, or PayPal account, for payment of Shipping Fees and any other fees including customs duties and Import VAT within seven (7) days of notification to you by email of the fees under the Pay Now option.

3\. The Auto-Pay option is not available in all countries.

b. By using the Services, you represent and warrant that the payment details provided on your Account are valid and correct, and that when your Shipment is accepted and processed by Aramex, payment will be made in full.

c. In the event payment is not made for any fees notified to you within thirty (30) days, we will be entitled to treat any Shipment held by us as an Uncollected Good.

**Customer Representations and Undertakings**

**11\. No illegal use**

You undertake not to use the Service and/or the Account for any illegal, immoral, obscene or fraudulent purposes or for any other purposes prohibited by Aramex, by the respective Shop and Ship Location, or any other applicable regulations. You further undertake that any use of the Service and/or Account shall be in compliance with all applicable federal, state, and/or local laws of the respective Shop and Ship Location, as well as other applicable international law, including laws related to the transportation and export of commercial matter, which may include without limitation laws related to banking, money laundering, trade sanctions and terrorist activities. Any shipment received in violation of this clause may result in the forfeiture, return to sender, or destruction of shipment, along with notification to the police and/or appropriate government authority.

**12\. We will not carry**

1\. You understand and agree that we will not carry, and you must not try to ship:

i. Any items classified as hazardous material, Dangerous Goods, articles that are prohibited or restricted by IATA (International Air Transport Associated), ICAO (International Civil Aviation Organisation), or any applicable government department or other relevant organisation; or

ii. firearms, bullion, works of art, negotiable instruments in bearer form, jewellery, precious metals, precious stones, lewd obscene or pornographic material, currency, stamps, deeds, hazardous or combustible material or other Dangerous Goods, cashier’s cheques, money orders, travellers’ cheques, industrial carbon and diamonds, antiques, plants or animals; or

iii. Government IDs and licenses, or items that claim to be, or that look similar to, government identification documents or other government issued documents. This includes uniforms, and badges or patches designed to look like official government-issue.  

b. Prohibited or restricted shipments, including shipments containing Dangerous Goods, will be forfeited, destroyed, or provided to government officials.

c. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, Aramex acceptance of any shipment containing Dangerous Goods does not mean that such shipment conforms to the applicable laws and regulations. You will be solely responsible for the compliance of the shipment with the applicable laws and regulations, in particular IATA Dangerous Goods Regulations, including but not limited to, the effective and sufficient packaging, packing, classification and documentation of the shipment. You are responsible to ensure that the shipment is acceptable for carriage and entry into the destination country or territory. All charges incurred for the carriage to and from countries or territories where entry is not permitted will be your expense. You will be liable for and shall defend, indemnify and hold harmless Aramex from all liability and/or claims against it based on injury to any person, damage or loss of property, or any other damage arising from any product liability, inadequate packing, mis-labelling, wrongful information, description or declaration you provide and for any other claim relating to the shipment or its carriage.

**13\. Animal skins, furs, feathers, hair, wildlife (from US)**

You accept and acknowledge that any shipments to be exported from the US that contain animal skin, furs, mink, alligator skin, python skin, feathers (including hair accessories) or any other wildlife will be held at the US Customs Department for inspection and may be seized or confiscated. You acknowledge and agree that you alone are liable for any costs involved if you try to export such items and that Aramex will not compensate you for such seized or confiscated shipments.

**14\. Restricted business**

You represent that your shipments do not relate to any restricted business, including but not limited to pornography, armaments, or any other restricted activities. You further represent that the goods being shipped are not destined for any country with which Aramex is prohibited from dealing as the result of any international or respective Shop and Ship Location law, legislation, regulation, directive, ordinance, treaty, etc.

**15\. Blacklisted name**

You represent that your name is not included in any blacklist issued by any respective Shop and Ship Location government or other worldwide regulatory body.

**16\. Export Declaration and other documentation**

You must provide Aramex with an Export Declaration for all packages of value exceeding amount identified in the [Export Declaration Value List](https://new.shopandship.com/faq/export-declaration-value-list) prior to shipment to your Delivery Address.

a. You must provide Aramex with invoices and/or other documentation related to the packages regardless of value at any time as requested by Aramex, or by Customs or any other Government Authority. You are solely responsible for the correctness and accuracy of all information you provide Aramex regarding the contents of your Shipment and the value.

b. You must provide Aramex with identification documentation and personal information upon request by Aramex or any official authority at its sole discretion.

**17\. Purpose of the Account**

You acknowledge and agree that your Account is provided by Aramex solely for the purposes of providing the Services as set out under these Terms and Conditions and that the Shop and Ship Location provided for each Account is a delivery address only and cannot be used for any other purposes.  You will not represent that any Shop and Ship Location address provided under your Account is your residence address or place of business for any purpose whatsoever. You undertake not to use the Account and/or the details of the Account for any other purpose including, but without limitation, using the Shop and Ship Location addresses and details of the Account as a billing address, personal mail delivery address, residential address, or as your personal contact details including without limitations on your website or business card. Any breach of this clause may lead to automatic deactivation of your Account at Aramex’s sole discretion, along with notification to the police and/or appropriate government authority.

**18\. Correct Name / Delivery Address**

Aramex will only ship packages that have the same name and Delivery Address as the individual or entity stated on the Application Form.  If Aramex receives any package to an Account the labelling of which does not match the applicable name or Delivery Address on the Application Form, then the shipment will be deemed an Uncollected Good or Unclaimed Good and Aramex reserves the right to deal with that Shipment in any lawful manner it considers appropriate, which may mean the package is discarded, destroyed, returned to sender, donated, or auctioned. You will be held accountable for any additional fees incurred on your account under this clause.

**19\. Account Security**

You must ensure that your password is kept secure and confidential and not revealed to any other person. You acknowledge that you are entirely responsible for your password and must notify Aramex immediately of any unauthorised use of your Account and/or password or any other breach of security relating to your Account. You acknowledge and agree that Aramex accepts no responsibility for any loss or damage occurring as a result of the fraudulent use of a password, and you release Aramex from all claims arising from the unauthorised use of your password. 

**Indemnification** **and Warranty**

20\. You warrant that all information provided by you is complete and accurate.

21\. You agree to protect, indemnify, release, safeguard, and hold harmless Aramex and its respective affiliates, subsidiaries, parent corporations, franchisees, officers, agents, and employees (“Aramex Indemnitees”) against any and all losses, damages, expenses, claims, demands, liabilities, judgments, settlement accounts, penalties, fines or other costs, including reasonable attorney fees and causes of action of any type or nature arising out of or in conjunction with the use of the Account and/or the Service, including without limitation any demands, claims, and causes of action for personal injury or property damage arising from:

a. failure of the respective Shop and Ship Location postal services, other relevant postal authority, or any commercial courier service to deliver on time or otherwise fail to deliver any item and/or package;

b. delay occasioned by treatment handling, examination or impounding of the Goods by any of the Government Authorities;

c. any misdescription or undervaluation provided for Customs purposes, whether intentionally or unintentionally;

d. breach by you of any applicable law or requirement of any Government Authorities; or

e. damage to or loss of any package or Account contents by any cause whatsoever, and from any violation by you of applicable international, federal, state or local laws.

22\. Without limiting any other provision of these Terms and Conditions, Aramex will not be liable for any costs, expenses, loss or penalties imposed or loss or damage incurred by any Aramex Indemnitee due to your Shipment or Goods being impounded by customs or other Government Authorities, and you hereby protect, indemnify, release, safeguard, and hold harmless each Aramex Indemnitee against any such cost, expense, fine, penalty or loss.

23\. Without limiting any other provision of these Terms and Conditions, Aramex will not be liable for any costs, expenses, loss, fines, or penalties imposed or loss or damage incurred by any Aramex Indemnitee due to your breach or non-compliance of any of these Terms and Conditions and you hereby protect, indemnify, release, safeguard, and hold harmless each Aramex Indemnitee against any such cost, expense, fine, penalty or loss.

**Limitation of Liability**

24\. Aramex will be responsible for your Shipment only while it is within Aramex’s custody or control, subject to the limitations of liability set out herein. 

25\. If the Shipment is transported by air and involves a stop in a country other than the country of departure, you understand and acknowledge that an Airfreight Convention may apply and may limit liability for loss or damage. Your claim for any loss or damage occurring during carriage by air, is against the airline carrier.  In the event of any loss or damage suffered by you while the Goods are in the possession of the airline carrier, Aramex will seek to recover amounts payable under the applicable Airfreight Convention on your behalf, and you will indemnify Aramex and hold it harmless against any claims for loss or damage to your Goods incurred while they were in the possession of the airline carrier.  If the Shipment is carried by international road transportation, the Convention for the International Carriage of Goods by Road (CMR) may apply. This convention limits Aramex’s liability for loss or damage. 

26\. You acknowledge that Goods moved by airfreight may necessarily involve a part of transport undertaken by other means. Where this is so, and no international treaty is applicable which covers the additional transport, your recovery of loss or damage, if any, is against the carrier and may exclude or substantially limit liability. In the event of any loss or damage suffered by you while the Goods are in the possession of a third-party carrier, Aramex will seek to recover from the carrier any amounts payable to you. You indemnify Aramex and hold it harmless against any claims for loss or damage to your Goods incurred while they are in the possession of the third-party carrier, where such carriage was necessary in order to complete the delivery of your Shipment.

27\. Without limiting the effect of clauses 20-23, and subject to clauses 28-29 below, in all cases where Aramex’s liability is not otherwise limited or excluded, Aramex’s liability shall be limited to whichever is the lesser between (i) the value of the Goods the subject of the Shipment at the time the Goods were delivered to Aramex, or (ii) US $100 per shipment, or its equivalent per shipment.

28\. To the extent that the liability of Aramex is limited by any Airfreight Convention, law or contract, and that limitation exceeds the limitation of liability pursuant to clause 27 above or Accountable Mail below, then the liability pursuant to that Airfreight Convention, law or contract shall apply.

29\. Any claim for loss or damage must be notified in writing to Aramex within seven (7) days of delivery of the Goods or of the date upon which the Goods should have been delivered. In any event, Aramex shall be discharged from all liability whatsoever in connection with the Services and/or the Goods unless proceedings are served within 90 days from delivery of the Goods (or from when they should have been delivered). In the event the Goods are fully compensated by Aramex for any reason, then you will need to send the damaged goods to Aramex in order to receive the compensation for the damaged goods.

30\. In addition to Aramex’s standard liability above, Aramex offers an additional protection plan for shipments against all risks of physical shipment loss or damage from any external cause. Click here for more details about the [Shop and Ship Additional Protection Service](https://new.shopandship.com/protect). You will be automatically enrolled for the Shop and Ship Additional Protection Service for each Shipment until such time you expressly opt-out of the Shop and Ship Additional Protection Service by updating the status in your Account.

**31\. Country Notices**.

a. Qatar Residents. This clause applies to Customers located in Qatar only. The Terms and Conditions are in compliance with the Electronic Commerce and Transaction Law No. 16 of 2010.

**32\. Accountable Mail**

In the event that Aramex agrees to accept Accountable Mail on your behalf, then in consideration for Aramex’s doing so, you agree that Aramex’s liability for loss or damage is limited to the lesser of (i) the value of the Goods, or (ii) US $100.

**33\. Consequential Losses**

Aramex will not be liable for any indirect, incidental, punitive or consequential loss or damage of any kind or any loss of profit, reputation, income, interest, opportunity, contract or bargain.

**Force Majeure**

34\. Aramex will not be liable to you for any delay, breach or failure to perform its obligations under these Terms and Conditions or any loss, costs or expenses you may incur which are caused or contributed to by an event beyond Aramex’s or its agents’ reasonable control, for example acts of God, fire, flood, natural catastrophes, failure or delay of suppliers or contractors, inability to obtain goods or services necessary to perform the Services, civil disturbances, insurrections, riots, wars (declared or undeclared), act of terrorism, strikes or lock-outs or stoppage or restraint of labour from whatever cause, whether partial or general. 

**Privacy**

35\. Aramex’s Privacy Policy applies to these Terms and Conditions.  A copy of the Privacy Policy is available [here](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions#pstab2).

**Change of Terms and Conditions, Service, and Fees**

36\. Aramex may add to or change or update these Terms and Conditions from time to time entirely at its own discretion and without notice to you. Any and all amendments to the Terms and Conditions shall be published on the Shop and Ship website ([www.shopandship.com](http://www.shopandship.com/)) and shall be effective on the date of publication thereof. You are responsible for checking these Terms of Conditions periodically to remain in compliance with these terms. Your use of the Account or ordering of any Services after any amendment to the Terms and Conditions shall constitute your acceptance of these Terms and Conditions, and you also agree to be bound by any such changes/revisions. You are advised to regularly check for any amendments or updates to the Terms and Conditions from time to time, as Aramex shall not be liable to compensate you for your failure to do so.

37 The Account Fee, Shipping Fees, and any other related charges stated herein or incidental hereto, as well as the Terms and Conditions are subject to change upon the sole discretion of Aramex at any time whatsoever, and without prior notice to you. There will be no refunds for your cancellation of the Service. Aramex may also change the shipping frequency at any time without providing prior notice to you.

**Termination**

38\. You agree that Aramex may terminate these Terms and Conditions for good cause at any time and without notice. Good cause shall include, but is not limited to: 

a. Your use of the Account for illegal, obscene, or fraudulent purposes or for any purpose prohibited by Aramex, the respective Shop and Ship Location, or other regulations;

b. Your failure to pay monies owed to Aramex when due; and

c. Your violation of any provision of these Terms and Conditions or any provision of any related operating rules and policies that are published by Aramex on Shop and Ship website ([www.shopandship.com](http://www.shopandship.com/)).

39\. You acknowledge that, for the purpose of determining good cause for termination of these Terms and Conditions as provided herein, the actions of any person authorized by you to use your Account or the Service will be attributed to you.

40\. Aramex reserves the right to immediately terminate the Service upon suspicion of any of the activities stated in clauses 11-15 above, and shall not be liable to compensate you for such termination.

41\. You may terminate these Terms and Conditions and close the Account by providing Aramex with 30 days prior written notice. Aramex reserves the right to refuse to accept any dispatch and/or package delivered to your Account after the termination date.

**Miscellaneous**

42\. Aramex may discard, destroy, donate, or auction your Goods within (a) thirty (30) days after receipt of unknown shipments, or (b) twenty-one (21) days after receipt of prohibited shipments, or high-value shipments, or shipments under an inactive account, if: (i) all applicable shipping charges have not been paid; (ii) the mail and/or packages were not clearly identified as belonging to you; (iii) you do not claim the mail or packages received to your Account, (iv) shipment was abandoned at customs, or (v) if Aramex has terminated the Terms and Conditions for good cause as set forth in clause 38 above. Notwithstanding the above, Aramex may destroy any pornographic materials or products and all other related content of whatever type immediately upon delivery to your Account.

43\. In the event your Shipment is categorized as on overweight or oversized shipment, then you will have seven (7) days to elect whether to the ship the overweight or oversized shipment through freight. At the end of the seven-day period, if you have not informed Aramex regarding your shipment method for the overweight or oversized shipment, then Aramex reserves the right to ship the overweight or oversized shipment through freight. Aramex shall notify you in the event your Shipment is classified as overweight or oversized upon receipt of the Shipment at the respective facility.

44\. In the event that you fail to pay the Shipping Fees, and other charges including custom duties and Import VAT, by the due date, Aramex reserves the right to deal with the package in any lawful manner it considers appropriate, which may mean the package is discarded, destroyed, donated, or auctioned.

45\. Any notice, request and/or any other correspondence pursuant to or in connection with these Terms and Conditions shall be in English and shall be sent to you to the email address specified in the Application Form or to any other email address that Aramex is earlier notified of.

46\. Any dispute arising under or in any way connected with these Terms and Conditions shall be subject, for the benefit of Aramex, to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of, and governed by the law of Dubai International Financial Center (DIFC) and you irrevocably submit to such jurisdiction, unless contrary to applicable law.

47\. If any section or any portion of any section of these Terms and Conditions is construed to be illegal, invalid or unenforceable, such provision or portion shall be deemed obsolete and deleted from these Terms and Conditions, while all other sections of these Terms and Conditions and the remaining portion of any section which is construed to be illegal, invalid or unenforceable shall continue in full force and effect. This Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between Aramex and you relating to your use of the Account and/or Service.

48\. Failure by Aramex to enforce at any time any term, provision, or condition of these Terms and Conditions, or to exercise any right herein, shall in no way operate as a waiver thereof.

**Last update**: February 9, 2023

**  
Flex Service Additional Terms and Conditions**

In addition to the above terms and conditions, S&S Members registered for Flex services agree to the following:

**1\. Description of Flex Services**. You are entitled to receive discounts and other benefits on specified products and services offered by Aramex ("**Benefits**").

a. A description of the Benefits are available online at  [Online Shopping & Shipping Membership Plans (shopandship.com)](https://new.shopandship.com/membership)

b. All Benefits are subject to discontinuation, change, modification, improvement or substitution without notice and Aramex makes no representations or warranties with respect to, and accepts no responsibility or liability for, out of date or erroneous information related thereto.

**2\. Membership Term; Renewals**. You will be entitled to all of the Benefits available to members of the Flex Service for the ensuing twelve-month period under the annual plan, commencing on the date of acceptance of your application for enrollment for each twelve-month period thereafter (the "Membership Term"). You have the option to select automatic renewal to ensure automatic renewal of their membership. In the event you do not select automatic renewal, you must renew their annual membership upon receipt of renewal notice.

**3\. Prices and Terms**

**(a) Flex Annual Subscription Fee****.** The current Flex subscription fee (the "Annual Subscription Fee"), is inclusive of VAT, will be automatically billed to your designated credit card account or other authorized billing source (e.g., debit card) on an annual recurring basis as authorized for automatic renewals upon registration. If you use a debit card as the designated credit card account, you acknowledge that **Aramex will not be responsible for any fees or penalties associated with insufficient funds, bounced checks or any other form of fee due to a charge of the Service Fee to a debit card provided by the Member**. You agree that you will pay the full Annual Subscription Fee for the whole year upfront. In the event you terminate your membership, the Annual Subscription Fee will not be refunded unless you meet the criteria for a refund as stated under Section 5 of this Agreement.

**(b) Renewal Fees**. If you opted for automatic renewal, and unless you cancel your membership in the Flex Service prior to the end of your then-current Membership Term, Aramex will automatically renew membership at the end of such then-current Membership Term as authorized upon registration and bill the then-current Annual Subscription Fee to the designated billing source. If the renewal charge fails, the subscription will expire. If you did not select the automatic renewal option at the time of registration, you will be required to pay the then-current Annual Subscription Fee upon renewal of your membership.

**(c) Taxes**. You are responsible for paying all applicable sales, use, transfer, value-added, or other taxes and all duties, and Import VAT, whether international, national, state, or local, however designated, which result from the purchase of our services. When Aramex is required to collect such taxes from you, Aramex may charge applicable taxes at the time of sale. You agree to pay all charges, including applicable taxes, in accordance with the billing terms in effect at the time the price or charge becomes payable. If an error has been made in the amount of taxes collected by Aramex with respect to your purchase, we reserve the right to process an additional charge in order to meet our obligations to collect such taxes in the correct amount as required by applicable law.

**(d) Modification of Pricing and Billing Terms**. We reserve the right at any time to institute new prices, and to change the amount of or the basis for determining any prices or charges with respect to the Flex Service, or charge taxes applicable to the sale of our services. You agree to pay all charges, including applicable taxes, in accordance with the billing terms in effect at the time the price or charge becomes payable. We reserve the right to modify the prices and charges at any time. For annual subscriptions, which are automatically renewed, such changes will become effective with your next billing cycle, following our written notification to you of such changes, unless you cancel your subscription within the allotted time frame.

**4\. Member Representation and Obligations**. In return for the discounts and benefits available under the Flex Service, you acknowledge your obligations to Aramex as follows: (a) you have read the "Shop and Ship Terms & Conditions" carefully, and understand the provisions of the Flex Service and the billing method for the payment of the Annual Subscription Fee; (b) you may cancel your membership in the Flex Service at any time prior to the conclusion of the then current Membership Term; (c) the benefits of membership in the Flex Service are not assignable without the express written consent of Aramex and you will use your membership only for personal, non-commercial use; (d) you agree not to share any proprietary information supplied you by Aramex including but not limited to promotion codes, discounts, incentives, and the like to any third-party, individual, entity or institution; and (e) you are responsible for any use or sales tax on Benefits that may be imposed by any state or federal taxing authority and such taxes, to the extent imposed.

**5\. Termination**

(a) Flex Registered Customers. You may terminate your subscription under this Agreement by sending an email directly to Shop and Ship Customer Service requesting termination of your membership. In order to qualify for full refund of the Annual Subscription Fee paid, you must terminate your subscription within thirty (30) days of registering for the subscription and you must have used the Services for a minimum of one shipment, but no more than three shipments, within the thirty (30) day period. You will not be entitled to a refund of the paid Annual Subscription Fee for any terminations after the thirty (30) days from registering for your subscription (or within thirty (30) days but not meeting the minimum shipment requirement under the Services). The effective date of such termination will be within seven (7) business days from date of receipt of notice. Upon termination of your subscription, you will not be permitted to register for a standard Shop and Ship account. In the event you initiate a reactivation of the subscription under this Agreement after a request for termination, the termination shall be null effective as of the date of such reactivation, and this Agreement will continue to be in effect. You will not be entitled to a refund of the paid Annual Subscription Fee upon receipt of one refund under this clause even after reactivation of your account. You shall not be entitled to any other refund as a result of the termination of your subscription to the Flex Service under this Agreement. In the event you do not renew your subscription, and did not use the Services for a minimum of one shipment, your account will be deactivated. In the event you do not renew your subscription, but did use the Services for more than one shipment, your account will automatically be converted to the standard Shop and Ship account.  

(b) Existing Shop and Ship Members Upgraded to Flex. You may terminate your Flex subscription under this Agreement by sending an email directly to Shop and Ship Customer Service requesting termination of your Flex membership. In order to qualify for full refund of the Annual Subscription Fee paid, you must terminate your subscription within thirty (30) days of upgrading to the Flex subscription and you must have used the Services under Flex for a minimum of one shipment, but no more than three shipments, within the thirty (30) day period. You will not be entitled to a refund of the paid Annual Subscription Fee for any terminations made after the thirty (30) days from registering for your subscription (or within thirty (30) days but not meeting the minimum shipment requirement under the Services). The effective date of such termination will be within seven (7) business days from date of receipt of notice. Upon termination of your subscription, your standard Shop and Ship account will automatically be your default account.

(c) We may terminate your right to use and/or access the Flex Service at any time in our sole discretion, with or without prior notice. We may also suspend your use of the Flex Service by disabling your username and/or password for any reason, including, but not limited to, cases in which we believe you have violated the terms of this Agreement or you are using the Flex Service in a manner inconsistent with the spirit of this Agreement or the general Terms of Use of our website. If we terminate your right to use and/or access to the Flex Service, without cause, we agree to refund to you the pro-rata portion of Annual Subscription Fee. Any determination of the amount to be returned to you in the event of any such termination shall be made by Aramex in its reasonable discretion, and shall be conclusive and binding.

**6\. Disclaimer of Warranty**. Aramex, its affiliates, and any third-party providers, as well as their officers, directors, shareholders, employees, and agents, do not guaranty and make no representations or warranties with respect to the accuracy, completeness, timeliness, or availability of the services. The products are provided “as is”. Neither we nor anyone else makes any warranties of any kind, either expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, warranties of merchantability, quality, accuracy, or fitness for a particular purpose. To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, all implied warranties, conditions, and other terms of any kind are hereby excluded. No oral or written information or advice given by any representative of us, or by anyone else, shall create any warranties.

**Last update**: January 10, 2018

TERM OF USE
===========

AUSTRALIA: To view the Shop & Ship Australia Terms of Use, please [](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/australia)[click here](https://www.shopandship.com/faq/terms-of-use-australia).

The terms of use for this Shop and Ship website (the “Website”) operated by AramexInternational LLC(“Aramex”) are applicable to all users (“you” and “your”) of the Website. By accessing the Website, you are deemed to agree to the following terms and conditions, the [Privacy Policy](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions) and any other relevant policies, terms and conditions and notices (collectively referred to as the “Terms of Use”) which are currently applicable or will be applicable to your use of the Website, without qualification.

If you do not agree to these Terms of Use, then you must stop using or accessing the Website.

1. **Intellectual Property Rights**
    
    All intellectual property rights in the contents of the Website are owned by Aramex, its affiliates, or its licensors and is protected by copyright, trademark, and other applicable laws.
    
    All content included on the Website, including without limitations text, graphics, logos, button icons, images, software, films, audio clips, downloads, interfaces, code, software, and the compilation of all content on the Website is the exclusive property of Aramex or its licensors and is protected by international copyright, trademark, and other applicable laws.
    
    All trademarks, logos, service marks and trade names displayed on this Website are the registered and/or unregistered trademarks of Aramex or its affiliates, or third party trademark or trade name holders.
    
    No part of the Website may be copied, reproduced, modified, transmitted, stored or exploited for commercial gain, as part of any other website or in any other form, whether electronic or otherwise, without the prior written consent of Aramex, except that you may print or download to your hard drive or other storage device extracts from the Website for your own personal or internal business use. Any other use, including the reproduction, modification, distribution, transmission, republication, display, or performance, of the content of the Website is strictly prohibited and constitutes breach of these Terms of Use. Your use of the Website does not entitle you to any intellectual property rights in the contents of the Website other than limited right of use granted to you under these Terms of Use. Any unauthorized use of the Website may result in a violation of intellectual property laws, the laws of privacy and publicity, and communication regulations and statutes.
    
2. **Use of Website**
    
    You may not use any “page-scrape”, “robot”, “spider” or other automatic device, program, algorithm or methodology, or any similar or equivalent manual process, to access, acquire, copy or monitor any portion of the Website, or in any way reproduce or circumvent the navigational structure or presentation of the Website, to interrupt or attempt to interrupt the operation of the Website, to obtain or attempt to obtain any materials, documents or information through any means not purposely made available through the Website.
    
    You may not attempt to gain unauthorized access to any portion or feature of the Website, or any other systems or networks connected to the Website, or to any of the services offered on or through the Website, by hacking, password “mining” or any other illegitimate means.
    
    We reserve the right, at any time, to restrict or terminate your access to, or use of the Website if you breach these Terms of Use or for any other reason whatsoever without notice. Termination or restricting your access or use will not waive or affect any other right or relief to which we may be entitled, at law or in equity.
    
3. **Linking**
    
    The contents of the Website may include links to third party websites (“Linked Sites”). These links are provided to you only as a convenience, and are beyond the control of Aramex.
    
    The inclusion of any Linked Site does not imply Aramex’s endorsement of that Linked Site. You acknowledge that your use of, or reliance on, any Linked Site will be at your own risk. Aramex recommends that you carefully review the privacy policy and all terms and conditions of Linked Sites that you visit.
    
    Aramex may prohibit links to the Website and you must remove or cease any link at Aramex’s request. You will not frame any part of the Website content by including advertising or other revenue generating material, without the prior written consent of Aramex.
    
4. **Registration**
    
    While registration is not required for you to use the Website, you will need to register through the Website to create a Shop and Ship Account (“Account”). There are numerous advantages in registering and creating an account with us. As a Shop and Ship Member, you will have access to the extra functionality available in the Website.
    
    In order to register and create a Shop and Ship Account you must complete the [Shop and Ship registration process](https://new.shopandship.com/signup). Once Aramex has received your application for registration, you will receive an email confirming that your application has been accepted. You must click on the link contained in this email to activate the registration. Aramex reserves the right to reject any application for registration at its sole discretion.
    
    By completing the registration process, you acknowledge that you are eligible for registration, and you warrant that you have, under the laws of your country, full legal capacity to enter contracts (including, without limitation, that you have attained the applicable legal age for entering contracts) and that the information you provide to Aramex for the purpose of registration is, at the time you provide it, current, complete and accurate, and not misleading or deceptive. All personal information you provide to us when you use the Website will be used and maintained in accordance with our Privacy Policy.
    
    You must log in using your username and password. You must ensure that your password is kept secure and confidential and not revealed to any other person. You acknowledge that you are entirely responsible for your password and you must notify Aramex immediately of any unauthorized use of your password or any other breach of security relating to your account. You acknowledge and agree that Aramex accepts no responsibility for any loss or damage occurring as a result of the fraudulent use of your password, and you release Aramex from all claims arising from the unauthorized use of your password.
    
    You acknowledge that Aramex assumes no responsibility whatsoever for ensuring that any information concerning you or your Company is current, complete or accurate and you agree to maintain and update any such information.
    
    You or Aramex may terminate your registration at any time and for any reason without written notice. Once your registration is terminated by Aramex, you will not be able to access any part of the Website intended for registered users without Aramex’s prior consent.
    
    Where you use the Website to request that Aramex carries out a task on your behalf, we will send an email to the address you submit during the registration process to confirm that we have received your request. Although Aramex makes every effort to ensure the services offered on the Website are as reliable as possible, the nature of the Internet means that we cannot be held liable for any requests inrespect of which we do not confirm to you that we have received.

6. **Charges**
    
    All prices listed on the Website are, to the best of Aramex’s knowledge, accurate at the time of printing. However, the Website may contain inadvertent inaccuracies or typographical errors. These will be corrected at Aramex’s discretion, as they are found.
    
    In addition, all prices listed are subject to change at any time without notice. The information on the Website may be updated regularly so inaccuracies may occur during the process.  
      
    Aramex reserves the right at any time to charge a fee for access to certain parts of the Website. However, in no event will you be charged for such access unless we obtain your prior agreement to pay.
    
    You acknowledge and agree that any rate or time estimate shown by the Rate Calculator or the Transit Time Calculator or other such tool on the Website for estimating a rate or time is an estimate only and may be different from the actual rates or times for domestic or international carriage of any shipments tendered to Aramex. This may be due to a number of causes including, without limitation, actual dimensions of your shipments, local charges and any unanticipated delays in shipping.
    
7. **Submitted Materials**
    
    You may submit material through the Website provided that:  
    a)you warrant that you own or control all rights (including all intellectual property rights) to any submitted material, and that the submitted material complies with these Terms of Use;  
    b)you grant Aramex a non-exclusive, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable and fully transferable license to use, reproduce, modify, adapt, publish, translate, create derivative works from, distribute and display your submitted material throughout the world in any media; and  
    c)you acknowledge there is no obligation of confidentiality in relation to the submitted material.
    
    You may not upload, distribute or otherwise publish any content on this Website that:  
    a)infringes the rights of third parties, including without limitation intellectual property rights;  
    b)breaches any applicable local, national or international law or regulation or these Terms of Use;  
    c)is fraudulent, or has any fraudulent purpose or effect;  
    d)is contrary to public policy and/or accepted moral standards, including but not limited to: obscene or offensive messages; pornographic or sexually explicit images; defamatory or libellous material; material harmful to minors; material promoting discrimination based on race, sex, religion, nationality, disability, sexual orientation or age; material likely to harass, upset, or alarm a third party or cause a third party to harm themselves;  
    e)is inconsistent with reasonable use of the Website.
    
8. **Indemnity**
    
    You agree to defend, indemnify and hold harmless Aramex and its affiliate companies and their respective officers, directors, employees, agents and representatives from any and all claims, losses, liabilities, expenses, damages and costs (including reasonable legal fees) arising or resulting directly or indirectly from or out of your breach of any of these Terms of Use, or any activity you conduct in connection with the Website. Aramex reserves the right, but not the obligation, at our own expense, to assume the exclusive defense and control of any matter otherwise subject to indemnification by you. In such instances, you agree to cooperate fully with Aramex in the defense of such matter.
    
9. **Export**
    
    You assume all responsibility for compliance with all laws and regulations of any country from which you may access the Website regarding access, use, export, re-export and import of any content appearing on or available through the Website.
    
10. **Data Entry**
    
    Aramex may retain any data that you provide in the course of using the Website and will do so in accordance with our Privacy Policy. You acknowledge that Aramex may delete this data at any time. You acknowledge that you are solely responsible for maintaining a back-up copy of such data and that Aramex will not be responsible for its loss or deletion.
    
11. **Terms of Carriage**
    
    You acknowledge and agree that domestic and international carriage by Aramex of any shipments tendered to Aramex through the Website will be governed by the terms, conditions and limitations of liability set out in the applicable terms and conditions, which are incorporated into these Terms and Conditions by reference.
    
12. **Limitation of Liability**
    
    The Website makes certain information and material available to you as a service, either through Aramex, its suppliers, or otherwise. The information and material provided on the Website is provided “as is”, has not been prepared by taking into account the particular objectives, situation or needs of any individual users, and is without warranties of any kind either express or implied.
    
    Aramex does not warrant or make any representations regarding the use or the results of the use of the Website or in Linked Sites in terms of their correctness, accuracy, timeliness, reliability, or otherwise. Aramex will not be responsible for errors or misstatements or be liable, whether in contract, tort (including negligence) or otherwise, for any loss or damage however caused (including direct, indirect, consequential, special losses, or loss of profits). You release Aramex from all claims arising from any statement or representation made on the Website. Your sole and exclusive remedy for any of the foregoing or any dispute with Aramex, our affiliates, and their respective officers, directors, employees, shareholders or agents of any of them, is to discontinue your use of the Website.
    
    To the fullest extent permissible pursuant to applicable law, Aramex excludes all responsibility and liability in relation to the Website, and disclaims all warranties, express or implied, including without limitation implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. Aramex does not warrant that the functions contained in the Website will be uninterrupted or error-free, that defects will be corrected, or that the Website or the server that makes it available, are free of viruses or other harmful components.
    
    To the maximum extent permitted by law, Aramex, you will indemnify Aramex, its officers and employees against all costs, expenses and damages incurred in connection with any claim brought by a third party against Aramex arising from a breach by you of any of the Terms of Use. You acknowledge that the limitation/exclusion of liability of Aramex, and your indemnity to Aramex, will also apply to all affiliates of Aramex, including any parent or subsidiary companies.
    
13. **Waiver**
    
    Aramex’s failure to enforce the strict performance of any provision of the Terms of Use will not constitute a waiver of its right to subsequently enforce such provision or any other provisions of the Terms of Use.
    
14. **Amendments**
    
    Aramex reserves the right to change the Terms of Use at any time and without providing you with notice of such changes. You agree that your continued use of the Website constitutes your acceptance of the modified Terms of Use, and you agree that all previous versions of the Terms of Use are superseded by the modified version. You should check these Terms of Use each time you access the Website to check for updates. These Terms of Use were last updated on March 25, 2015.
    
15. **Headings**
    
    Headings in these Terms of Use are for convenience only and do not affect the interpretation of these terms and conditions.
    
16. **Severability**
    
    If any of these conditions shall be deemed invalid, void, or for any reason unenforceable, that condition shall be deemed severable and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of the remaining conditions.
    
17. **Law**
    
    Your use of the Website and these Terms of Use are governed by and construed in accordance with the laws and regulations of the Emirate of Dubai and the federal laws of the United Arab Emirates applicable in the Emirate of Dubai.
    
18. **Contact**
    
    If you have any questions, concerns or complaints in relation to the Website or the Terms of Use please contact Aramex [customer service team](https://new.shopandship.com/contact).

PRIVACY POLICY
==============

**AUSTRALIA: To view the Shop & Ship Australia Privacy Policy, please [](https://new.shopandship.com/termsandconditions/australia)[click here](https://www.shopandship.com/faq/privacy-policy-australia).**

The Aramex Group (“**Aramex**”) has drafted this Privacy Policy in order to explain Aramex’s policy regarding the use of any personal information it collects on Aramex customers and users of other services provided by Aramex (such as Aramex’s websites and applications). This Privacy Policy’s goal is to allow those customers and users to understand how their personal information may be handled by Aramex, as well as the rights they have in relation to their personal information.

In general, Aramex will handle personal information shared by customers or users, as well as other information which may be gathered by Aramex in connection with services provided, in a lawful, fair and transparent manner. Aramex has considered internationally recognised principles on the protection of personal data when defining its policies, such as the principles of purpose limitation, storage limitation, data minimisation, data quality and confidentiality.

**Table of Contents**

1. **_Controller and Data Protection Officer_**
2. **_Personal Data processed_**
    1. **Name, contact details and other Personal Data**
        * Aramex retail outlets
        * Aramex websites
        * Aramex applications
        * Consignees
    2. **Data related to users’ devices**
        * Aramex mobile applications
    3. **Data related to your location**
        * Aramex mobile applications
    4. **Call recordings**
    5. **Shipment Inspection**
    6. **Shipment history**
    7. **Special categories of Personal Data**
        * Aramex websites and applications
    8. **Personal Data related to criminal convictions and offences**
    9. **Other persons’ Personal Data**
        * Aramex websites and applications
    10. **Browsing data**
        * Aramex websites and applications
    11. **Cookies, SDKs and tracking technologies**
        * Aramex websites
        * Aramex applications
3. **_Purposes of processing_**
4. **_Grounds for processing and mandatory / discretionary nature of processing_**
5. **_Recipients of Personal Data_**
6. **_Transfer of Personal Data_**
7. **_Retention of Personal Data_**
8. **_Data subjects’ rights_**
9. **_Amendments_**

**1\. Controller and Data Protection Officer**

The controller regarding all personal data processing carried out via websites or applications managed by Aramex is **Aramex International LLC**, with registered offices at P.O. Box 95946, Dubai, United Arab Emirates.

**Aramex International LLC** acts as a joint controller with each individual local Aramex Station, regarding personal data related to customers of a given local Aramex Station, or to consignees of shipments delivered by (or on behalf of) that local Aramex Station. Please refer to the relevant section on the Aramex website (available [here](https://www.aramex.com/us/en/support/find-office)) in order to understand which Aramex Station may act as a controller regarding those personal data in your location.

When acting as joint controllers, **Aramex International LLC** and the relevant local Aramex Station are jointly responsible for ensuring that all rules regarding the handling of your personal data are respected. You can exercise your rights as a Data Subject against either one by:

* Submitting an online support request ([here](https://www.aramex.com/support/submit-privacy-request)); or
* Reaching out to your relevant local Aramex Station.

Aramex has appointed a Group Data Protection Officer. To contact the Aramex DPO, please submit an online support request ([here](https://www.aramex.com/support/submit-privacy-request)).

Aramex has also appointed a representative for local Aramex Stations which are established outside of the EU/EEA, under Art. 27 GDPR:

**Aramex Nederland B.V.**

Fokkerweg 300, 1438 AN, Oude Meer, P.O. Box 728, 2130 AS Hoofddorp, the Netherlands.

To contact the Aramex EU/EEA Representative, please submit an online support request ([here](https://www.aramex.com/support/submit-privacy-request)).

2. **Personal Data processed**

When providing services to customers, users or consignees, whether through physical retail outlets, websites or applications managed by Aramex (jointly referred to as the “**Aramex Services**”), Aramex will collect and process information regarding those customers / users / consignees (as individuals) which allows their identification either by itself, or together with other information which is available. Aramex may also be able to collect and process information regarding other persons in this same manner, where those customers / users / consignees choose to provide it to Aramex.

This information may be classified as “**Personal Data**”, and can be collected by Aramex both when shared by customers / users / consignees (e.g., upon signing up for an account on an Aramex website, when placing an order for delivery services, when preparing a shipping document at retail outlets), by analysing users’ behaviour (e.g., when browsing Aramex websites or using Aramex applications) or when disclosed to Aramex by other sources (e.g., Aramex’s customers, entities providing sanction-list screening services to Aramex).

These Personal Data may include the following categories:

1. **Name, contact details and other Personal Data**

* _Aramex retail outlets_

When requesting services from Aramex at a physical retail outlet, you will be asked to submit Personal Data concerning yourself. This may include your name, surname, telephone number, address, delivery address, copies of your government-issued identification cards and information related to your credit card (if you use these cards as a payment method). You can find the relevant information relating to each Aramex’s physical retail outlet stores [here](https://www.aramex.com/us/en/support/find-office).

* _Aramex websites_

In various sections of Aramex’s websites – including, in particular, account creation pages and forms – you will be asked to submit Personal Data concerning yourself, such as your name, phone / mobile number, e-mail address, gender, date of birth, country of residence and postal address, as well as, in certain cases, information related to your company of employment and position in that company. Where services provided over these websites require payment, you will also need to disclose information as to your preferred mode of payment (e.g., PayPal, credit card).

Whenever you participate in surveys, promotions or contests which may be available on Aramex’s websites, as well as whenever you decide to communicate with Aramex via contact details provided on those websites (or, otherwise, by telephone with Aramex Customer Service), Aramex may collect additional Personal Data which you choose to provide, as far as this is necessary in order to address your request or query. This is also the case regarding information which you choose to disclose in certain sections of Aramex websites which allow your participation in public forums, or the sending of messages directly to Aramex.

* _Aramex applications_

When creating an account on Aramex applications, you will be asked to submit Personal Data concerning yourself, such as your name (first and last), mobile number, e-mail address and information regarding the credit card to be used as a payment method – number, name, expiry date and card verification number – as well as your shipping address (based on your location, or selected on a map).

* _Consignees_

Aramex may receive Personal Data concerning yourself from its customers, in order to allow Aramex to complete shipments from those customers to you, as a consignee. In this case, Aramex may also collect Personal Data from you upon shipment delivery. This may include, in particular, your name, surname, telephone number, address and delivery address, as well as, in certain cases, copies of your government-issued identification cards and information related to your credit card (if you use these cards as a payment method, where applicable).

2. **Data related to users’ devices**

* _Aramex mobile applications_

When choosing to install Aramex applications, you grant permission to Aramex to set up the selected application on your mobile device (“ **Device**”), as well as to access Personal Data and other information stored on your Device which are needed in order to successfully install the application (e.g., Device model, operating system version, screen resolution, network connection type, language, etc.). This collection of information is inherent to the process of installing and setting up Aramex’s applications and, as such, you may not object to it unless you uninstall the application from your Device.

Once an Aramex application has been installed, you may be asked to allow the application to send and read SMS messages from your Device, in order to send you an SMS verification code and to grant you automatic access to the application, upon successful receipt of this code. When using Aramex applications, access may also be requested to your Device’s storage (e.g., when you register shipping addresses on an application), camera (e.g., so that you can scan your credit card in order to insert its details as a payment method in the applications) and Internet access, among other functions where necessary.

3. **Data related to your location**

* _Aramex mobile applications_

Once you have installed an Aramex application, you may be asked to consent to the application accessing your Device’s location, even when you are not using the application, as well as to your Device’s map functionalities. This is meant to allow Aramex to provide more precise and useful Aramex Services to you via the application, in particular, by allowing you to pinpoint your location, register a shipping address based on your current location (as opposed to searching on a map), track your shipments in real-time (on the day of delivery), ensure correct delivery of your shipments, and so on.

If you believe that the continuous access to your location is too invasive, you can configure your Device in a way to share your position only when the applications are in use. If even this is too invasive, you can always revoke the sharing of your position from the Device settings and simply provide a physical address, zip code or state for the Aramex Services you are interested in (or manually pin your relevant address on a map within the applications).

4. **Call recordings**

When you contact Aramex’s Customer Support team over the phone, Aramex will store a recording of the call held between you and the Aramex Customer Support agent – this is done, primarily, to retain evidence of service-related requests or complaints handled over the phone (to allow Aramex to demonstrate how they were handled), and for service quality monitoring/training purposes. You will be notified of this through a pre-recorded message presented at the start of the call.

5. **Shipment Inspection**

In order to lawfully provide the Aramex Services, Aramex may be required to physically inspect the shipments which are to be delivered in connection with those Aramex Services, in particular to confirm that any applicable legal shipment restrictions (e.g., due to country of origin or destination, or type of goods shipped) or trade embargoes are respected.

These inspections will be carried out only to detect whether the terms of any applicable legal restrictions regarding incoming and outgoing shipments are respected. In particular, Aramex will not carry out an in-depth inspection of any documents or other items which might reveal Personal Data on the sender, consignee or third persons, unless this is strictly necessary for these compliance purposes. As a result of an inspection, if your shipment is rejected (due to a conflict with, for example, applicable legal import or export restrictions), Aramex will either attempt to arrange for the return of the shipment to its origin (where legally possible to do so) or destroy the shipment, as required by the applicable laws.

Aramex maintains logs of all inspection activities performed, including details on the origin and destination countries of the shipment, the name of the shipper and consignee, a general description of the shipment contents (e.g., “documents”, “shower curtains”, etc.), the country of origin of those contents, the contents’ Harmonized System (HS) code, and the air waybill number for the shipment.

6. **Shipment history**

Aramex will keep logs of details, actions taken and interactions had with you in connection with deliveries made at your request (as a shipper), as well as of deliveries made to you (as a consignee). This may include information such as shipment order date/time, shipment contents (generic description), shipper details (name, contact details, billing address), consignee details (name, contact details, delivery address), delivery method, delivery status, delivery date/time, delivery location, number of failed delivery attempts, preferred communication channel for delivery updates, number of returned deliveries, and so on.

These data will be collected from shipment records, but also from logs generated from the different channels through which you may interact with Aramex (such as our applications and websites, our call centres and SMS/instant messaging channels).

7. **Special categories of Personal Data**

Aramex does not typically need to process more sensitive categories of Personal Data, such as data revealing your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, or other types of sensitive information relating to you, such as your genetic data, biometric data or data concerning your health, sex life or sexual orientation, in order to provide the Aramex Services. Though this information may potentially be inferred from some of the Personal Data collected by Aramex (e.g., goods to be shipped), it is not the intention of Aramex to process those categories of Personal Data, and those categories of Personal Data will not be specifically processed for any purpose (other than to provide the Aramex Services).

* _Aramex websites and applications_

Certain areas of Aramex websites and applications may include free text fields where you can write messages to Aramex, or otherwise allow you to post various types of content, which may contain Personal Data. Where these fields are completely free, you may use them to disclose, or may post content which discloses (inadvertently or not) more sensitive categories of Personal Data such as data revealing your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership. The content you upload in these fields may also (inadvertently or not) include other types of sensitive information relating to you, such as your genetic data, biometric data or data concerning your health, sex life or sexual orientation

Aramex asks that you do not disclose any sensitive Personal Data in these free text fields or in your posts on Aramex websites or applications, unless you consider this to be strictly necessary. While Aramex does not intend to collect sensitive Personal Data on customers or website / application users (except where this is explicitly stated by Aramex), this may occur where those individuals voluntarily choose to disclose those data.

If you do disclose sensitive Personal Data to Aramex in this manner, then Aramex will process those Personal Data only to the extent that they are adequate, relevant and not excessive regarding the purposes of processing described in this Privacy Policy (see below, Purposes of processing). This will be done, in particular, where necessary to perform a contract with you or to answer a request you make, or otherwise where Aramex can be said to have a legitimate interest in processing those data, due also to the fact that, when you decide to disclose sensitive Personal Data through Aramex websites and applications, you may be manifestly making those Personal Data public.

8. **Personal Data related to criminal convictions and offences**

In order to lawfully provide the Aramex Services, Aramex may be required to screen customers / users / consignees against applicable government denied parties, sanctions and watch lists, as well as politically exposed persons databases. Aramex may also be required to confirm whether its customers or users are allowed to export goods outside of their country of location upon requesting Aramex Services, and/or that customers / users / consignees meet other requirements necessary for customs clearance purposes.

This process may involve asking for a copy of your national identification documents or passport, as well as accessing information on prior sanctions or limitations (of a criminal nature or otherwise) which may have been imposed upon you by order of a court or other competent authority. Aramex will only access this information where this is authorised under the applicable law, and solely to the extent necessary to comply with any legal requirements which may apply.

As a result of a screening exercise, if you are identified as a partial or potential match on any applicable lists, you may be asked to provide further information to confirm your identity (such as a copy of your national identification documents or passport, if you have not been asked for this already). If you are identified as an exact match, Aramex will not be able to complete your shipment; in this case, Aramex will either attempt to arrange for the return of the shipment to its origin (where legally possible to do so) or destroy the shipment, as required by the applicable laws.

Aramex maintains logs of all screening activities performed, including details on the origin and destination countries of the shipment, the name of the shipper and consignee, a general description of the shipment contents (e.g., “documents”, “shower curtains”, etc.), the country of origin of those contents, the contents’ Harmonized System (HS) code, and the air waybill number for the shipment.

9. **Other persons’ Personal Data**

When requesting Aramex Services, you may decide to provide information on other persons which is relevant for the correct provision of those services (e.g., where you wish to have a delivery made to another person – i.e., a consignee – you will be required to provide information on the consignee). This may include information such as those persons’ name, delivery address and phone number.

In any situation where you decide to share Personal Data related to other persons, you will be considered as an independent data controller regarding those Personal Data, and must assume all inherent legal obligations and responsibilities. This means, among other things, that you must fully indemnify Aramex against any complaints, claims or demands for compensation for damages which may arise from the processing of this Personal Data, brought by the third parties whose information you provide to Aramex.

As Aramex does not collect this information directly from these third parties (but rather collects them, indirectly, from you), you must make sure that you have these third parties’ consent before providing any information regarding them to Aramex; if not, then you must make sure there is some other appropriate grounds on which you can rely to lawfully give Aramex this information.

* _Aramex websites and applications_

Additionally, as mentioned in the previous section, certain areas of the Aramex websites / applications include free text fields where you can write messages to Aramex, or which otherwise allow you to post various types of content. These messages and content may (inadvertently or not) include Personal Data related to other persons. Other sections of Aramex’s websites may ask you to submit Personal Data related to third parties, such as other contact persons in your company or your relatives who are employees of Aramex.

The final two paragraphs of the above subsection (regarding your liability for Personal Data on other persons which you choose to share with Aramex, and your obligation to ensure that you are lawfully entitled to do so) also apply in full in this case.

10. **Browsing data**

* _Aramex websites and applications_

The operation of Aramex’s websites and applications involves the use of computer systems and software procedures, which collect information about website and application users as part of their routine operation. While Aramex does not collect this information in order to link it to specific users, it is still possible to identify those users either directly via that information, or by using other information collected – as such, this information must also be considered Personal Data.

This information includes several parameters related to your operating system and IT environment, including your IP address, location (country), the domain names of your computer, the URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) addresses of resources you request on the websites or applications, the time of requests made, the method used to submit requests to the server, the dimensions of the file obtained in response to a request, the numerical code indicating the status of the response sent by the server (successful, error, etc.), and so on.

These data are used to compile statistical information on the use of the websites and applications, as well as to ensure their correct operation and identify any faults and/or abuse.

11. **Cookies, SDKs and tracking technologies**

Aramex may process your Personal Data through cookies, SDKs (Software Development Kits) and similar technologies to improve your experience on Aramex’s websites or Aramex applications.

* _Aramex websites_

Information regarding the use of cookies on each of our websites can be found in the Cookie Policy made available on each website.

* _Aramex applications_

Information regarding the use of SDKs and tracking technologies on Aramex applications can be found in the SDK Policy which is made available on each applications.

3. **Purposes of processing**

Aramex intends to use the above Personal Data, collected in connection with the provision of Aramex Services, for the following purposes:

* Generally, to allow Aramex to provide Aramex Services to you, including (without limitation) express, freight and logistics services, as well as to allow you to request and receive Aramex Services which are specifically delivered through Aramex’s websites and applications (“**Service Provision**”). This may include the use of Personal Data in order to (for example):

* Create shipment labels and airway bills;
* Track shipment deliveries;
* Provide updates to customers on shipment status through online portals;
* Contact consignees in order to narrow down and confirm delivery addresses, and ensure successful completion of deliveries;
* Allow users to create registered accounts and participate in forums and discussions on Aramex websites and applications;
* Process payments for Aramex Services, including those requested via Aramex websites or applications;
* Sending alerts to users regarding Aramex applications, via push notifications on user Devices.

* To gain a better understanding of your preferences in relation to the Aramex Services, based on prior interactions we have had with you (such as deliveries made for you), and better tailor Aramex Services to you, in order to increase their efficiency and improve your experience (“ **Service Analytics**”). This may include the use of Personal Data in order to (for example):

* Complete or correct inaccurate delivery addresses;
* Identify the timeslots which you prefer for receiving shipments;
* Identify whether you prefer picking up shipments yourself (at a retail store or drop-off point), or having shipments delivered to you;
* Identify your preferred communication channel for shipment updates (SMS, e-mail, apps, phone calls, etc.);
* Determine the likelihood of any obstacles which may arise to correct and timely service delivery.

* For future marketing, promotional and publicity purposes (“ **Marketing**”). This may include the use of Personal Data in order to (for example):

* Allow you to participate in contests and promotions held or sponsored by Aramex;
* Send you direct marketing messages, through e-mail, SMS, push notifications (on mobile devices) or telemarketing calls;
* Send you surveys and other messages aimed at market research, through e-mail, SMS, push notifications (on mobile devices) or telemarketing calls;
* Show you advertisements related to Aramex goods and services on other websites and platforms, by sharing limited amounts of your Personal Data (for example, your e-mail address) with third-party website/platform providers.

* To create a profile of you as a user of Aramex’s websites / applications, through the use of Marketing cookies or SDKs (see Cookies, SDKs and tracking technologies, above) and by collecting and analysing information on the preferences you select and choices you make in Aramex’s websites / applications, as well as through your Device data (e.g., IFDA). This information will be used to personalise the Aramex Services provided through the websites and applications, where possible, to suit your preferences and choices, as well as to serve you with information and advertisements which may be relevant to you and your interests. All algorithms involved in this processing are regularly tested, to ensure the processing’s fairness and control for bias (“**Profiling**”);

* To keep records of requests, complaints or transactions carried out over the phone between you and an Aramex Customer Support agent, to prove that those requests, complaints or transactions took place at a given date and time, as well as for quality assurance purposes – namely, to incidentally confirm that Aramex Customer Support agents provide high-quality support to Aramex customers (“ **Call Recording**”);

* For compliance with laws which impose upon Aramex the collection and/or further processing of certain kinds of Personal Data (“ **Compliance**”);

* For development and administration of Aramex’s websites and applications, in particular by use of data analytics regarding how you and other users use those websites / applications, as well as the information and feedback you provide, in order to improve Aramex’s offerings (“**Analytics**”);

* To prevent and detect any misuse of Aramex’s websites or applications, or any fraudulent activities carried out through the Website (“ **Misuse/Fraud**”).

4. **Grounds for processing and mandatory / discretionary nature of processing**

Aramex’s legal bases to process your Personal Data, according to the purposes identified in Purposes of processing above, are as follows:

* **Service Provision** : processing for these purposes is necessary to provide the Services and, therefore, is necessary for the performance of a contract with you. It is not mandatory for you to give Aramex your Personal Data for these purposes; however, if you do not, Aramex will not be able to provide any Services to you.

* **Service Analytics** : processing for this purpose is generally based on Aramex’s legitimate interests, namely, in improving the efficiency and effectiveness of the Aramex Services, as well as improving the Aramex customer/consignee experience. You are allowed to object to this, and also to ask for more information about the assessments carried out by Aramex regarding its legitimate interests, by sending us a support request (please see Data subjects' rights, below, for more information).

* **Marketing** : processing for this purpose is based on your consent. It is not mandatory for you to give consent to Aramex for use of your Personal Data for these purposes, and you will suffer no consequence if you choose not to (aside from not being able to receive further marketing communications from Aramex). Any consent given may also be withdrawn at a later stage (please see Data subjects' rights, below, for more information).

* **Profiling** : processing for this purpose is based on your consent, given by accepting the use of Marketing cookies or SDKs (see Cookies, SDKs and tracking technologies, above). It is not mandatory for you to give consent to Aramex for use of your Personal Data for this purpose, and you will suffer no consequence if you choose not to (aside from not being able to benefit from greater personalisation of your user experience regarding Aramex’s websites and applications). Any consent given may also be withdrawn at a later stage (please see Data subjects' rights, below, for more information).

* **Call Recording** : processing for this purpose is generally based on Aramex’s legitimate interests, namely, in retaining evidence of requests, complaints and transactions carried out with Aramex customers over the phone – so that Aramex can demonstrate when they took place, and ensure that they are properly addressed by Aramex – and in ensuring that Aramex Customer Support agents provide high-quality assistance to Aramex customers (by incidentally reviewing calls held by each agent). You are allowed to object to this, and also to ask for more information about the assessment carried out by Aramex regarding its legitimate interests, by sending us a support request (please see Data subjects' rights, below, for more information).

In some jurisdictions, Aramex may not be legally allowed to record phone calls you take part in without your consent. Where this is the case, processing for this purpose will be based on your consent. In this case, it is not mandatory for you to give consent to Aramex for use of your Personal Data for this purpose, though you may be redirected to another communication channel in order to address your support request with Aramex. Any consent given may also be withdrawn at a later stage (please see Data subjects' rights, below, for more information).

* **Compliance** : processing for this purpose is necessary for Aramex to comply with its legal obligations. When you provide any Personal Data to Aramex, Aramex must process it in accordance with the laws applicable to it, which may include retaining and reporting your Personal Data to official authorities for compliance with tax, customs or other legal obligations.

In some cases – notably regarding screening of senders/consignees against existing blacklists or the inspection of shipments – Aramex may base the related processing activities on its legitimate interests, namely, in ensuring that any applicable shipment restrictions are complied with. You are allowed to object to this, and also to ask for more information about the assessment carried out by Aramex regarding its legitimate interests by sending us a support request (please see Data subjects' rights, below, for more information).

* **Analytics** : processing for this purpose is generally based on Aramex’s legitimate interests, namely, in understanding how users interact with Aramex’s websites and applications through collected browsing data and to improve them accordingly, with the aim to providing a better user experience. You are allowed to object to this, and also to ask for more information about the assessment carried out by Aramex regarding its legitimate interests by sending us a support request (please see Data subjects’ rights, below, for more information).

Where Statistics cookies or SDKs are specifically used to collect this information (see Cookies, SDKs and tracking technologies, above), this is based on your consent, given by accepting the use of Statistics cookies or SDKs (see Cookies, SDKs and tracking technologies, above). It is not mandatory for you to give consent to Aramex for use of your Personal Data for this purpose, and you will suffer no consequence if you choose not to. Any consent given may also be withdrawn at a later stage (please see Data subjects’ rights, below, for more information).

* **Misuse/Fraud** : processing for this purpose is generally based on Aramex’s legitimate interests, namely, in preventing and detecting fraudulent activities or misuse of Aramex’s websites and applications (for potentially criminal purposes), and ensuring the security of Aramex’s websites and applications. You are allowed to object to this, and also to ask for more information about the assessment carried out by Aramex regarding its legitimate interests by sending us a support request (please see Data subjects’ rights, below, for more information).

5. **Recipients of Personal Data**

Your Personal Data may be shared with the following list of persons / entities (“**Recipients**”):

* The specific Aramex customer on behalf of which Aramex is providing Aramex Services to you, where are a consignee;
* Entities engaged in order to screen Aramex customers and consignees against applicable government denied parties, sanctions and watch lists, as well as politically exposed persons databases, as required or authorised by the applicable law;
* Individuals or entities engaged in order to provide Aramex Services on Aramex’s behalf (e.g., couriers, call centre agents, service partners, hosting providers or e-mail platform providers), as well as persons authorised by Aramex to process Personal Data needed to carry out activities strictly related to the provision of the Aramex Services (e.g., Aramex employees), who are bound to obligations of confidentiality, may only process Personal Data under Aramex’s instructions and must comply with security measures set by Aramex;
* Persons, companies or professional firms providing Aramex with advice and consultancy regarding accounting, administrative, analytics, legal, tax, financial and debt collection matters related to the provision of Aramex Services;
* Entities engaged as data processors, to carry out processing activities related to **Marketing**, **Profiling** and/or **Analytics** on Aramex’s behalf, where you have consented to processing of your Personal Data for these purposes (e.g., SMS engines, certain third-party cookie providers);
* Third-party providers of websites and online platforms, to carry out processing activities related to **Marketing** (in particular, displaying Aramex advertisements on their websites / online platforms):

* Google ([Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en));
* Facebook/Instagram ([Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation));

* Persons authorised to perform technical maintenance (including maintenance of network equipment and electronic communications networks);
* Companies within the Aramex Group (which may also assist in providing Aramex Services to a customer / user / consignee, depending on his/her location); and
* Public entities, bodies or authorities to whom your Personal Data may be disclosed, in accordance with the applicable law or binding orders of those entities, bodies or authorities;

6. **Transfer of Personal Data**

Considering Aramex’s worldwide presence and business operations, your Personal Data may be transferred to Recipients located in several different countries. In particular, whenever you rely on Aramex Services for any cross-border operations (such as the delivery of a shipment from one country to another), Personal Data may be transferred to the receiving country.

Aramex implements appropriate safeguards to ensure the lawfulness and security of these Personal Data transfers, in particular regarding transfers of Personal Data from within the EEA to outside the EEA. As a rule, whenever [an adequacy decision from the European Commission](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/adequacy-decisions_en) is not available for the recipient country, Aramex enters into agreements with recipients containing [standard data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/standard-contractual-clauses-scc_en), or otherwise relies on any other more appropriate lawful transfer mechanisms available under the applicable data protection law.

7. **Retention of Personal Data**

Personal Data processed for **Service Provision** will be kept by Aramex for the period deemed strictly necessary to fulfil such purposes – in any case, as these Personal Data are processed for the provision of Aramex Services, Aramex may continue to store this Personal Data for a longer period, as may be necessary to protect Aramex’s interests concerning potential liability linked to the provision of Aramex Services.

Personal Data processed for **Service Analytics**, as well as **Analytics** which are based on Aramex’s legitimate interests (analytics performed on browsing data; see Purposes of processing, above), will be aggregated as soon as feasible, and thus will be kept as Personal Data only for the period deemed strictly necessary to allow for such aggregation.

Personal Data processed for **Analytics**, where based on your consent (analytics performed using Statistical cookies or SDKs; see Purposes of processing, above), will be kept by Aramex from the moment you give consent until the moment you withdraw the consent given. Once consent is withdrawn, Personal Data will no longer be used for these purposes, although it may still be kept by Aramex, in particular as may be necessary to protect Aramex’s interests concerning potential liability linked to this processing.

Personal Data processed for **Marketing** and **Profiling** will be kept by Aramex from the moment you give consent until the moment you withdraw the consent given. Once consent is withdrawn, Personal Data will no longer be used for these purposes, although it may still be kept by Aramex, in particular as may be necessary to protect Aramex’s interests concerning potential liability linked to this processing.

Personal Data processed for **Call Recording** (in particular, the recordings themselves) will be kept by Aramex, as a rule, for up to 1 year from the date on which a call to the Aramex Customer Support team is made. In jurisdictions where Aramex may only legally record phone calls you take part in with your consent, call recordings may be retained from the moment you give consent until the moment you withdraw the consent given.

However, in the event that selected call recordings are reasonably necessary for Aramex to establish, exercise or defend against legal claims, or otherwise to protect Aramex’s interests concerning potential liability linked to the provision of the Aramex Services, they may be kept for a longer period.

Personal Data processed for **Compliance** will be kept by Aramex for the period required by the specific legal obligation or by the applicable law. In particular, logs related to screening or inspection exercises carried out by Aramex will be kept for up to 5 years, after which they will be archived. Archived logs will only be accessed where this is reasonably necessary for Aramex to establish, exercise or defend against legal claims, or otherwise to protect Aramex’s interests concerning potential liability linked to the provision of the Aramex Services.

Personal Data processed for **Misuse/Fraud** will be kept by Aramex for as long as deemed strictly necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected, unless you validly object to the processing of your Personal Data for these purposes (please see Data subjects' rights, below, for further information).

8. **Data subjects’ rights**

Under the Regulation, you, as a data subject, are entitled to exercise the following rights before Aramex, at any time:

* Access your Personal Data being processed by Aramex (and/or a copy of that Personal Data), as well as information on the processing of your Personal Data;

* Correct or update your Personal Data processed by Aramex, where it may be inaccurate or incomplete;

* Request erasure of your Personal Data being processed by Aramex, where you feel that the processing is unnecessary or otherwise unlawful;

* Request the restriction of the processing of your Personal Data, where you feel that the Personal Data processed is inaccurate, unnecessary or unlawfully processed, or where you have objected to the processing;

* Exercise your right to portability: the right to obtain a copy of your Personal Data provided to Aramex, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, as well as the transmission of that Personal Data to another data controller; or

* Withdraw your consent to processing (for **Marketing**, **Profiling**, **Analytics** and, where applicable, for **Call Recording**).

Regarding processing purposes which are based on our legitimate interests (see Purposes of processing, above) **you are also entitled to object to the processing of your Personal Data**, based on relevant grounds related to your particular situation, which you believe must prevent Aramex from processing your Personal Data. If you do, then we will only continue processing your Personal Data for the purpose in question if we can demonstrate that we have a compelling legitimate interest to continue doing so, or if we need to in order to establish, exercise or defend against any legal claims.

Please note that most of the personal information you provide to Aramex can be changed at any time, including your e-mail preferences, by accessing the user profile you can create on Aramex’s websites and applications.

You can also withdraw consent regarding processing for **Marketing** by selecting the appropriate link included at the bottom of every marketing e-mail message received. Specifically, regarding **Marketing** carried out via push notifications, you can withdraw this consent via the options made available through Aramex’s applications, or through your Device’s settings:

* If you have an IOS Device, please see more information here: [https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201925#manage-alerts](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201925#manage-alerts) .

* If you have an Android Device, please see more information here: [https://support.google.com/android/answer/9079661?hl=en](https://support.google.com/android/answer/9079661?hl=en) .

You can withdraw consent regarding processing for **Profiling** and **Analytics** performed using Marketing or Statistics cookies, SDKs or other tracking technologies by using the consent management platform made available on Aramex websites / tracking settings made available on Aramex applications.

Aside from the above means, you can also exercise your rights described above by sending us a support request via Aramex’s websites, by filling out the form available here.

In any case, please note that, as a data subject, you are also entitled to file a complaint with the competent supervisory authorities for the protection of Personal Data, if you believe that the processing of your Personal Data carried out by any Aramex Station is unlawful. If you are located within the EU, you are entitled to file these complaints with supervisory authorities located (1) in the Member State of your habitual residence, (2) in the Member State of your place of work or (3) in the Member State where you believe the unlawful processing occurred.

9. **Amendments  
    **

This Privacy Policy entered into force on **November 15, 2022**. Aramex reserves the right to partly or fully amend this Privacy Policy, or simply to update its content, e.g., as a result of changes in applicable law. Aramex will inform you of any substantial changes as soon as they are introduced (through a pop-up on Aramex’s website, and through e-mail notifications sent to customers / users / consignees included in Aramex’s mailing lists). Changes will be binding as soon as they are published.

Fraud Prevention
================

**Our Commitment to Protection**

At Aramex, we take protecting our customers' sensitive information seriously and are constantly monitoring our information and data to prevent fraudulent or suspicious behavior.

We strive to protect you and encourage you to be aware of any potential fraudulent behavior by malicious parties using the Aramex brand. Below are some tips for how you can recognize fraud to ensure that sensitive information is kept secure.

**Recognize Fraud**

Recognizing phishing and scam e-mails and other types of communications is key to protecting yourself against fraud and theft. Common warning signs of online scams include:

* **Requests for Money:** Unexpected requests for money in return for delivery of a package, often with a sense of urgency, and used to trick people into sending money and provide personal information such as usernames, passwords, and credit card details.
* **Requests for Personal Information:** Requests for personal and/or financial information for the purpose of committing theft, identify theft and other crimes.
* **Deceptive Domain Names:** Links to misspelled or slightly altered website addresses (e.g. aramx.com / aramxpress.org / aramexcourier). If you doubt the integrity of any website using the Aramex brand, please visit our global website: [www.aramex.com](http://www.aramex.com/) or contact Aramex Global Customer Care Center at [GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com](mailto:GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com).

**Types of Fraud**

Fraudulent Emails and Email Scams: These are the most common online scams. Such emails attempt to trick you by pretending to come from a reputable source, such as from Aramex (for example from what appears to be an Aramex email). They will try to get you to share sensitive personal, account information or send a payment. They may also ask you to enroll in winning a prize or entering a competition.

We urge customers to be suspicious of any request not coming directly from an Aramex employee or domain name.

**Identity Theft:** This occurs when someone tricks you into disclosing/providing personal, financial or account information. Posing as well-known companies, information thieves usually send out e-mails or contact you by telephone asking you to reply or direct you to a fraudulent web page that asks you to provide personal information, such as your credit card number or account password, or even your Aramex credentials.

**Credit Card Fraud:** In some instances, credit card fraud occurs when someone's physical credit card is lost or stolen by another party who uses it. Credit card fraud is driven primarily by the compromise of credit card account data during their normal course of usage. Stolen credit card data is often used to attempt fraudulent online purchases.

**Spam and Viruses:** In our industry, customers usually receive an email suggesting that Aramex is attempting to deliver a package and request that you open the email attachment to prompt the delivery. This attachment may be a computer virus. Unless you are expecting to receive an email like this, please do not open the attachment and report it to Aramex Global Customer Care Center at ([GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com](mailto:GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com)).

**Package Tracking Emails:** In some cases, customers receive an email containing a tracking number. This number can be verified by inserting it into the “Track Shipment” box on [www.aramex.com](http://www.aramex.com/). If there are no tracking results returned, it is not a valid tracking number, and Aramex did not send the email. Please report this email to Aramex Global Customer Care Center at ([GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com](mailto:GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com)).

**Activation Key:** Messages with activation keys are only sent to complete your registration after downloading the Aramex mobile app. If you receive messages without attempting to register on our mobile app, then we urge you to ignore it. Aramex will never ask for you activation key over phone or email; for your account’s security, please do not share your key with anyone.

**Doing Our Part**

The security of your personal information is important to us. At Aramex, we recognize industry standards and employs appropriate administrative, technical and physical security safeguards to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use and other unlawful forms of processing. We continually invest in latest world-class technologies to minimize all potential risks for the benefit of our customers, and we remain committed to ensuring we meet the most stringent security requirements and fostering a security culture within our organization. Our commitment to Information Security is always audited and has been recognized by international accreditation bodies such as the British Standards Institution (BSI), as our security measurements are ISO 27001:2013 certified.

Our corporate website and mobile App use several security techniques including secure servers. All your personal information, including your credit card details, are encrypted before leaving your browser or device. Our payment platform has also been certified for compliance with payment card and data security industry standards (i.e. PCI-DSS).

**Doing Your Part**

Aramex will keep these measures under review and enhance them from time to time as necessary. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your login information, including your password. Please note that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, Aramex cannot guarantee the absolute security of your personal information.

**Contact Us**

For any comments or questions on Aramex’s Customer Protection and Fraud Prevention Measures, please contact Aramex Global Customer Care Center at ([GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com](mailto:GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com)).

**Disclaimer:**

_Aramex does not, and will not request you to provide any personal or payment information through traditional mail or via email. Being aware and protecting your sensitive information is the best way to prevent fraud. If you receive a request for personal or payment information through these types of communications, please do not reply or cooperate with the sender and immediately report the case to Aramex Global Customer Care Center at (_[_GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com_](mailto:GlobalCareCenter@aramex.com)_)._

_Aramex accepts no responsibility for any costs, charges or payments made as a result of fraudulent activity. It is important to be mindful of the above ways your information and data can be stolen to prevent any fraud in the future._ 

SDK POLICY
==========

The Aramex Group (“**Aramex**”) has drafted this SDK Policy in order to explain Aramex’s policy regarding the use of any personal information it collects on visitors and users of the Aramex applications through SDKs (Software Development Kits) and similar technologies. This SDK Policy’s goal is to allow those visitors and users to understand how their personal information may be handled by Aramex through SDKs, as well as the rights they have in relation to their personal information.

In general, Aramex will handle personal information collected through SDKs, in a lawful, fair, and transparent manner. Aramex has considered internationally recognised principles on the protection of personal data when defining its policies, such as the principles of purpose limitation, storage limitation, data minimisation, data quality and confidentiality.

The controller regarding all personal data processing carried out via SDKs and similar technologies that Aramex uses on Aramex applications, is **Aramex International LLC**, with registered offices at P.O. Box 95946, Dubai, United Arab Emirates.

You can exercise your rights as a Data Subject against Aramex by submitting an online support request ([here](https://www.aramex.com/support/submit-privacy-request)), or by sending a written request to Aramex at the following address: [privacy@aramex.com](mailto:privacy@aramex.com). Aramex has also appointed a Group Data Protection Officer. To contact the Aramex DPO, please submit an online support request ([here](https://www.aramex.com/support/submit-privacy-request)).

**This SDK Policy is a part of Aramex’s Privacy Policy**. For more information regarding Aramex’s personal data processing activities, please read the Aramex’s Privacy Policy (accessible [here](https://www.shopandship.com/en/privacy-policy)).

**SDKs and Tracking Technologies**

SDKs and similar technologies are systems that allow applications to record and/or read information on your Device. In general, these technologies allow an analysis of the use of an application, with the goal to avoid malfunctions and improve users’ experience.

In its applications, Aramex uses SDKs and similar technologies which may be managed directly by Aramex, or otherwise provided by third parties. These third parties act, as the case may be, as independent data controllers from Aramex (using the data they collect for their own purposes and under terms defined by them) or as data processors for Aramex (processing personal data on Aramex’s behalf). For further details on how these third parties may use your information, please refer to their privacy policies (provided below whenever available).

Different SDKs apply depending on the operating system which your device is using:

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **iOS SDKs** |     |     |     |
| **SDK name** | **Used in App(s)** | **SDK type and purposes** | **Further Information** |
| Alamofire | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* API networking library | * [SDK description](https://github.com/Alamofire/Alamofire) |
| AlamofireNetworkActivityIndicator | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Controls the visibility of the network activity indicator on iOS, using Alamofire | * [SDK description](https://github.com/Alamofire/AlamofireNetworkActivityIndicator) |
| CocoaPods Keys | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Ensures greater security for tokens and keys used by our applications | * [SDK description](https://github.com/orta/cocoapods-keys) |
| Cosmos | Aramex App | **Preference SDK**<br><br>* Allows users to provide star ratings on our applications | * [SDK description](https://github.com/evgenyneu/Cosmos) |
| CryptoSwift | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Ensures appropriate data encryption | * [SDK description](https://github.com/krzyzanowskim/CryptoSwift) |
| Facebook SDK for iOS | Aramex App | **Statistics SDK**<br><br>* Used to track the number of users who decided to install our applications after clicking on a social media advertisement | * [Privacy Policy (Facebook Open Source)](https://opensource.facebook.com/legal/privacy/) |
| Firebase Cloud Messaging | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary/Marketing SDK**<br><br>* Allows for push notifications to be sent to all, or specific users | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase Crashlytics | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows us to detect application crashes in real time, and reports information on those crashes | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase Dynamic Links | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows our applications to link users to other websites and/or applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase In-App Messaging | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary/Marketing SDK**<br><br>* Allows for push notifications to be sent to all, or specific users | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase Remote Config | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Facilitates the process of making changes to our applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase Performance Monitoring | Aramex App | **Statistics SDK**<br><br>* Gathers data on our applications’ technical performance | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Google Analytics | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Statistics SDK**<br><br>* Gathers data on users’ behaviour on our applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Google Maps | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Preference SDK**<br><br>* Allows Google Maps to function within our applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| iCarousel | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows in-app horizontal sliding features (known as “carousels”) | * [SDK description](https://github.com/nicklockwood/iCarousel) |
| Material Showcase for iOS | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows in-app showcase viewing | * [SDK description](https://github.com/nicklockwood/iCarousel) |
| MSPeekCollectionViewDelegateImplementation | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows in-app horizontal scrolling | * [SDK description](https://github.com/MaherKSantina/MSPeekCollectionViewDelegateImplementation) |
| PMKAlamofire | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* API parsing | * [SDK description](https://github.com/PromiseKit/PMKAlamofire) |
| pop | SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Animation engine | * [SDK description](https://github.com/facebookarchive/pop) |
| PubNub | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows push notification updates and shipment live tracking | * [Privacy Policy (PubNub)](https://www.pubnub.com/legal/privacy-policy/) |
| Reachability.swift | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Checks for an Internet connection | * [SDK description](https://github.com/ashleymills/Reachability.swift) |
| SDWebImage | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Web image loader | * [SDK description](https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImage)<br>* [Data Collection Practices](https://sdwebimage.github.io/DataCollection/index.html) |
| Siren | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Informs users when an application update is available | * [SDK description](https://github.com/ArtSabintsev/Siren) |
| SwiftKeychainWrapper | Aramex App | **Preference SDK**<br><br>* Allows saving user data to the iCloud Keychain (if used) | * [SDK description](https://github.com/jrendel/SwiftKeychainWrapper) |
| TPKeyboardAvoiding | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Moves text fields out of the way of the keyboard | * [SDK description](https://github.com/michaeltyson/TPKeyboardAvoiding) |
| Whisper | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Message and in-app notification display | * [SDK description](https://github.com/hyperoslo/Whisper) |
| Keychain Services | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allow us to save the sensitive data e.g. (user tokens, cached API requests) & user device info it enables us to confirm the user device ID when the courier sign in. | * [SDK description](https://developer.apple.com/documentation/security/keychain_services#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP30000897-CH203-TP1) |
| NSUserDefaults | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allow us to locally save values that are being used in the application. | * [SDK description](https://developer.apple.com/documentation/foundation/nsuserdefaults) |
| CLLocationManager | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to receive courier location | * [SDK description](https://developer.apple.com/documentation/corelocation/cllocationmanager) |
| App Setting | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to navigate the user to the app setting from the application | * [SDK description](https://pub.dev/packages/app_settings) |
| Permission handler | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to request permission from the user e.g. (access to user location, notifications) | * [SDK description](https://pub.dev/packages/permission_handler) |
| Location | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to receive the location of the courier while the app is in the background | * [SDK description](https://pub.dev/packages/location) |
| Device info | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to see the device info e.g. (device id) | * [SDK description](https://pub.dev/packages/device_info_plus) |
| ReCaptcha | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Prevents spams or bots to floor our backend APIs | * [SDK Description](https://github.com/alexeichhorn/ReCaptcha) |
| Translized | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to use multiple languages support | * [SDK Description](https://github.com/translized/iOS-SDK) |
| ScrollingPageControl | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>allow us to use page controller indicator depends on pages count | * [SDK Description](https://github.com/EmilioPelaez/ScrollingPageControl) |
| lottie-ios | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Use to Load Lottie animation | * [SDK Description](https://github.com/airbnb/lottie-ios) |
| MarketingCloudSDK | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Marketing push notification get | * [SDK Description](https://github.com/salesforce-marketingcloud/MarketingCloudSDK-iOS) |

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Android SDKs** |     |     |     |
| **SDK name** | **Used in App(s)** | **SDK type and purposes** | **Further Information** |
| Facebook SDK for Android | Aramex App | **Statistics SDK**<br><br>* Used to track the number of users who decided to install our applications after clicking on a social media advertisement | * [Privacy Policy (Facebook Open Source)](https://opensource.facebook.com/legal/privacy/) |
| Firebase Cloud Messaging | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary/Marketing SDK**<br><br>* Allows for push notifications to be sent to all, or specific users | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase Crashlytics | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows us to detect application crashes in real time, and reports information on those crashes | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase Dynamic Links | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows our applications to link users to other websites and/or applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase In-App Messaging | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary/Marketing SDK**<br><br>* Allows for push notifications to be sent to all, or specific users | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase Remote Config | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Facilitates the process of making changes to our applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Firebase Performance Monitoring | Aramex App | **Statistics SDK**<br><br>* Gathers data on our applications’ technical performance | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Glide | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Loads images on our applications | * [SDK description](https://bumptech.github.io/glide/) |
| Google Analytics | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Statistics SDK**<br><br>* Gathers data on users’ behaviour on our applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Google Places | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Preference SDK**<br><br>* Provides contextual location services, identifying relevant local businesses, points of interest and geographic locations near you | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Google Play Core Library | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows application updates to be prompted and installed during application use<br>    <br>    **Preference SDK**<br>    <br>* Allows users to provide ratings on our applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Google Maps | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Preference SDK**<br><br>* Allows Google Maps to function within our applications | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Material Components for Android | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Used to assist in the design and development of our applications’ user interfaces | * [Privacy Policy (Google)](https://policies.google.com/privacy)<br>* [Use of information collected from websites and apps using Google services (Google)](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) |
| Material Tap Target Prompt | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Displays a showcase on the applications’ maps for first-time users | * [SDK description](https://github.com/sjwall/MaterialTapTargetPrompt) |
| PubNub | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* Allows push notification updates and shipment live tracking | * [Privacy Policy (PubNub)](https://www.pubnub.com/legal/privacy-policy/) |
| Retrofit | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>* API networking library | * [SDK description](https://square.github.io/retrofit/) |
| what3words | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Preference SDK**<br><br>* Allows locations/addresses to be identified by 3-word combinations | * [Privacy and Cookie Policy](https://what3words.com/privacy/) |
| NotificationCompat | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to show user-facing notifications to the user’s device from a server, or generate them locally from the app. | * [SDK description](https://developer.android.com/reference/androidx/core/app/NotificationCompat) |
| SharedPreferences | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to locally save values that are being used in the application. | * [SDK description](https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/SharedPreferences) |
| FusedLocationProviderClient | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to receive courier location | * [SDK description](https://developers.google.com/android/reference/com/google/android/gms/location/FusedLocationProviderClient) |
| Safety net | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Prevents spams or bots to floor our backend APIs | * [SDK description](https://developer.android.com/training/safetynet) |
| Huawei safetydetect | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Prevents spams or bots to floor our backend APIs for Huawei devices only | * [SDK description](https://developer.huawei.com/consumer/en/hms/huawei-safetydetectkit/) |
| Huawei Locations | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to take the user location for adding user address (needed user permission) for Huawei devices only | * [SDK description](https://developer.huawei.com/consumer/en/hms/huawei-locationkit/) |
| Huawei Maps | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allow us to show map view for Huawei devices only | * [SDK description](https://developer.huawei.com/consumer/en/hms/huawei-MapKit/) |
| Marketing Cloud | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK/Marketing SDK**<br><br>Allows for push notifications to be sent to all, or specific users | * [SDK description](https://salesforce-marketingcloud.github.io/MarketingCloudSDK-Android/) |
| org.joda money and converter | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Tools and Utils to help convert the decimals for the Money | * [SDK description](https://www.joda.org/) |
| Dotsindicator | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>To Show Page Indicator for cards | * [SDK description](https://github.com/tommybuonomo/dotsindicator) |
| Scrollingpagerindicator | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>To Show Page Indicator for cards | * [SDK description](https://github.com/tinkoff-mobile-tech/ScrollingPagerIndicator) |
| Pinentryedittext | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Uses for for phone number OTP | * [SDK description](https://github.com/alphamu/PinEntryEditText) |
| Lottie | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allows to use animated images | * [Privacy Policy](https://lottiefiles.com/page/privacy-policy)<br>* [SDK description](https://github.com/airbnb/lottie-android) |
| appsflyer | Aramex App<br><br>SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK/Marketing SDK**<br><br>Gathers data on users’ behaviour on our applications | * [Privacy Policy](https://github.com/airbnb/lottie-android)<br>* [SDK description](https://dev.appsflyer.com/hc/docs/android-sdk) |
| translized | Aramex App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allows to translate and fix text | * [Privacy Policy](https://www.translized.com/privacy-policy)<br>* [SDK description](https://docs.translized.com/docs/sdk/android) |
| rtl-viewpager | SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>To Displaying pages | * [SDK description](https://github.com/duolingo/rtl-viewpager) |
| RxAndroid | SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Used for Reactive programming | * [SDK description](https://github.com/ReactiveX/RxAndroid) |
| rxpermissions | SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Used for Reactive programming handling android system permissions | * [SDK description](https://github.com/tbruyelle/RxPermissions) |
| android-reactive-location | SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Used for Reactive programming handling location | * [SDK description](https://github.com/mcharmas/Android-ReactiveLocation) |
| Card IO | SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>Allows Scanning Credit Cards for easier card registration | * [SDK description](https://github.com/card-io/card.io-Android-SDK) |
| dagger | SNS / AGS App | **Necessary SDK**<br><br>dependency injection framework | * [SDK description](https://dagger.dev/) |

You can choose not to consent to the use of certain SDKs / tracking technologies, or otherwise withdraw your consent (and thereby block or delete) certain SDKs / tracking technologies, via the tracking settings made available to you on Aramex’s applications.

If you wish to prevent your Device’s operating system from sharing your Personal Data with Aramex or with the third parties mentioned for profiling purposes, you can also do so by setting up your Device appropriately.

* If you have an IOS Device, please see more information here: [https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074).
* If you have an Android Device, please see more information here:
    * [https://support.google.com/android/answer/9079631?hl=en&ref\_topic=7650590](https://support.google.com/android/answer/9079631?hl=en&ref_topic=7650590);
    * [https://www.androidguys.com/tips-tools/how-to-disable-personalized-ads-on-android/](https://www.androidguys.com/tips-tools/how-to-disable-personalized-ads-on-android/).

**AMENDMENTS  
  
**This SDK Policy entered into force on May 21, 2023. Aramex reserves the right to partly or fully amend this SDK Policy, or simply to update its content, e.g., as a result of changes in applicable law. Aramex will inform you of any substantial changes as soon as they are introduced (through a pop-up on Aramex’s applications, and through e-mail notifications sent to customers / users / consignees included in Aramex’s mailing lists). Changes will be binding as soon as they are published.

REST ASSURED?
-------------

REST ASSURED?
-------------

Then make the next move. Join now and become a global online shopper today!

Got questions? Get answers.
---------------------------

Got questions? Get answers.
---------------------------

We told you all about our terms and conditions. Now, if you have any questions, check our FAQs to get the answers.

Got questions? Get answers.
---------------------------

Got questions? Get answers.
---------------------------

We told you all about our terms and conditions. Now, if you have any questions, check our FAQs to get the answers.

Oops! Something went wrong.
---------------------------

Oops! Something went wrong.
---------------------------

We couldn't complete your last action. It may be something on our end. Please try again in a moment. if the problem persists, please contact us.

Confirm

Your Flex account will expire on

Tracking number not valid

Activation email has been sent.

Activation email has not been sent.

Email has been activated successfully

Error while activating email

Change password email has been sent.

Change password email has not been sent.

Your password was changed successfully !

Failed to change your password. Please try again later.

Password must meet the following:

At least 1 letter

At least 8 characters long

At least 1 capital letter's

At least 1 small letter

At least 1 number

At least 1 special character

START SHIPPING TODAY
--------------------

START SHIPPING TODAY
--------------------

Sign up for Shop & Ship and get $10 off the membership.

Login
-----

WELCOME BACK!
-------------

It's great to see you again. Enter your registered Shop & Ship details to access your account pronto!

Email 

Password 

Forgot password We can help

Reset Password
--------------

Reset Password
--------------

Don't worry, to reset your password just enter your email below

Email 

Back to Login

Wrong user name or password

The account you are trying to login with was deactivated, to activate [click here](#)

HELLO AGAIN!
------------

HELLO AGAIN!
------------

Change Password
---------------

Change Password
---------------

Please note that your password will change for both shopandship.com & aramex.com

New Password 

Confirm 

Shop & Ship is an online shipping delivery service from Aramex | Copyright ©**[Aramex](https://www.aramex.com/ae/en/)** International LLC | All rights reserved
